Curriculum Vitaé



Sanjeev Bhandari

------ Career Summary ------

Senior professional with more than 15 years of collective experience in business consulting and investment banking. Extensive experience in strategy development, operations management, and business expansion.

Key skills set include: Business strategy, M&A, Venture Capital, Operations Management **Industry experience:** ICT, Travel, Automotive, Engineering, & Manufacturing

------ Professional Experience ------

CEO & Director - India

SICMA India Pvt. Ltd. – Jan'2014 - Feb'2016: A 100% subsidiary of SICMA Italy - one of the largest mechanized agricultural equipment companies in Europe. www.sicma.it

- Initially acted as the India advisor and developed the India entry strategy; set-up and managed the entire operations including the assembly plant, hiring of the team (management & workers); all regulatory and statutory approvals
- Developed the local supply chain strategy to achieve the desired target costs; led negotiations with suppliers to achieve the desired objectives vis-à-vis product, price, and timelines
- Profit & Loss responsibility; led the sales, purchase, finance, quality, production departments to achieve quarterly and yearly targets
- Reported directly to the members of the Board in Italy on a regular basis

India Director

Autobahn, UK – Jul' 2011-Dec'2013: A 100% subsidiary of Autobahn Group, UK - Fast Lane Automotive offers world leading vehicle data systems in India, with master records of all vehicles registered in India, with input from industry stakeholders and related datasets .www.fastlaneindia.com

- Advised the company on its India entry strategy in setting-up of the entire operations
 - Managed the operations for two years as the Indian Director and board member
 - Set-up the entire eco-system by forging relationships with key clients and partners across India
 - Managed and supported the technical team to develop the systems in India

Vice President - Consulting

TMG Advisory Group Pvt. Ltd. – Since January 2010-Jan'14: TMG Advisory is an international boutique consulting firm, with presence in India, Italy & the UK offering business consulting and investment banking services worldwide. www.tmgadvisory.com

Role & selected contributions:

- Advising clients on market entry strategy for India and leading consulting assignments ranging from M&A, private equity and joint ventures. Thereafter, if required, taking up role of CEO / India Director to lead the business operations of the clients in India
 - Autobahn UK Ltd. 2011-2013: Strategy development and advice to UK based automotive company for the Indian market
 - Other transactions managed between: 2010-11
 - Joint venture for a Swiss Railway equipment company in India specializing in tunneling systems
 - India entry strategy development and execution for a Swiss Defense company
 - Advisor to a Chinese meter manufacturing company on strategic partnership with an Indian Co.

Associate Vice President (Consulting) - May'06 – Dec'2009

Avista – Houlihan Lokey Pvt. Ltd.: A boutique investment banking and business consulting firm, providing services in the areas of strategy consulting, M&A, private equity, investment banking and emerging markets advisory

Role & selected contributions:

- It involved working on assignments ranging from M&A advisory; Greenfield investment strategy; and Private Equity transactions; The projects included end-to-end transaction service from initial feasibility to structuring of the transaction
- Responsible for leading teams of associates/senior associates who work on independent strategy consulting/ private equity and M&A transactions mainly in manufacturing, telecom and automotive sector

Transactions:

- Worked on setting up the entire Nokia Park in Chennai; Advising the supply chain of Nokia in setting up the Indian operations
- Acquisition mandate for a Finnish Chemicals Conglomerate
- Advised a European Chemicals company on their M&A transaction and also developed the entry strategy for its water chemicals business
- Worked on a strategic partnership mandate for a Finnish Power equipment company
- Set up the supply chain for an Italian telecom equipment company; supported them in setting up their India operations

Trade & Investment Advisor (Automotive) - August' 04- May-06

UK Trade & Investment (UKTI): A consulting firm with 220 offices worldwide, providing business consulting to British enterprises in the area of international business strategy.

- Strategy development & consulting: Designing clients' operations and marketing strategy for India through close interaction with its senior management team. Understanding their business objective visà-vis India and developing strategy for the same
- Business development and client servicing: Worked closely with the International Sector Group (ISG) team in the UK and specific industry organizations/partners to develop new business opportunities for the sector team. It involved visiting UK for meeting prospective clients, both SME and large business houses, across sectors of significant importance e.g. automotive, engineering and aerospace

Transactions: JV of UK based design firm with an Indian car designing company Acquisition of a British forging company by an Indian automotive group

Asst. Manager-Marketing - May'03-June'04

Galileo India Pvt. Ltd.: A wholly owned subsidiary of Galileo International, one of the leading global travel distribution services company, with its headquarters in Parsippany, New Jersey, USA.

 Marketing-Communications & Brand management: Developed, executed, and managed comprehensive marketing programs and communication strategies across all marketing disciplines including, advertising & promotions, web marketing, event marketing, and sales collateral

Manager-Marketing & Strategic Alliance - Jan'1998-April'03

BRAIN Group: Is one of the leading media groups in the Asian region with headquarters in Singapore and 7 offices spread over Southeast Asia and Europe

- Interface with the client and creative team of the company to develop and strategize the marketing & communication plan for clients across industries
- Provided support to the Head office in Singapore for day-to-day activities including project update, marketing and business development; Account Management responsibilities for clients like Schlumberger, ABB, Ericsson and other key clients across industries

----- Professional & Educational Qualifications -----

- Masters degree in Business Administration (MBA) from the Indian Institute of Foreign Trade (IIFT), New Delhi. Specialization in International Business (2005)
- Post graduate diploma in *Public Relations & Advertising* from Centre for Mass Media, New Delhi (1997-98)
- Four years advanced diploma in *German language* from Goethe Institute, New Delhi.(1997-2001)
- Bachelor of Commerce from Delhi University (1997)
- AISSC Examination from Manav Sthali School, New Delhi (1994)

Training and certifications

Knowledge Management certification from Quality Assurance of India (QAI) (2005) International Market Research-Managing and Implementation (2004) Certificate course in Transcultural Awareness & Competence Training (2004)

Academic Projects

Supply Chain-A competitive edge for the Indian automotive industry Foreign Direct Investment in the UK-The Indian experience World Trade Organization-Impact of Tariff reductions on India

------ Interests & Activities ------

- Doing research in the areas of international business, macroeconomic issues and technology
- Voice-over artist in English and German for documentary films. Few of them, produced by the Ministry of External Affairs, screened at the Berlin Film Festival, 2001
- Playing Golf, Music

Languages (written & spoken): *Hindi, English, & German*

Date: June' 2016

Place: New Delhi

Sanjeev Bhandari